Guide to the Fales Library Collection of Publishers Galleys MSS.553
Fales Library and Special Collections
Fales Library Collection of Publishers Galleys
1860-1969
Fales Library and Special Collections
Fales Library
MSS.553
1.5 Linear Feet in 18 flat-file folders and 8 custom flat boxes.
This collection includes galleys for books and journals. It was assembled by the Fales Library and Special Collections.
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Biographical / Historical
The Fales Library was given to NYU between 1957 and 1966 by DeCoursey Fales in memory of his father, Haliburton Fales. The collection documents the history of the novel in English, broadly representing developments in narrative and prose fiction from 1700 to the present through original editions, manuscripts and other materials. This foundational collection established literature as one of the core collection areas of what is now NYU Special Collections. The publishers galleys assembled in this collection represent the work of prominent 19th and 20th century writers and document the final stages of the editing process.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials found in collection; there is no documentation concerning the provenance of these materials.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains publisher galleys for various books, journals, and book translations. The collection includes galleys of books by well-known authors including Flannery O'Connor, Ernest Hemingway, Erich Maria Remarque, William S. Burroughs, Richard Wright, and P. D. Wodehouse as well as several translations of the works of August Strindberg translated by Arvid Paulson.
Literature publishing.; Galley proofs.
- Chalis the doubter, Undated (Flat-file-folder 1)
- A forgotten genius: Charles Whitehed, Undated (Flat-file-folder 2)
- El Corno Emplumado, Issue #24 [Incomplete], October 1967 (Flat-file-folder 3)
- El Corno Emplumado, Issue #25, January 1968 (Flat-file-folder 4)
- El Corno Emplumado, Issue #27, July 1968 (Flat-file-folder 5)
- El Corno Emplumado, Issue #28, October 1968 (Flat-file-folder 6)
- El Corno Emplumado, Issue #29, January 1969 (Flat-file-folder 7)
- El Corno Emplumado, Issue #31, May-June 1969 (Flat-file-folder 8)
- Concerning Jude the Obscure by Havelock Ellis, Undated (Flat-file-folder 9)
- Ladies World, My Life (Foreward) by Frank Harris, Undated (Flat-file-folder 10)
- Intro to Beasley's by Arthur Machen and Burns' Love Songs by Hugh MacDiarmid, Undated (Flat-file-folder 11)
- In Memoriam James Joyce by Christopher M. Grieve [Hugh MacDiarmid], Undated (Flat-file-folder 12, Flat-file-folder 13)
- Vessel of Wrath by W. Sommerset Maugham, Undated (Flat-file-folder 14)
- In Search for Divinity by George Moore, Undated (Flat-file-folder 15)
- Water I Slip into at Night by Margaret Randall, Undated (Flat-file-folder 16)
- Amateur and Professional Fees for Performing Licenses, Shaw One, What a Playwright should do with his first play, Undated (Flat-file-folder 17)
- In the Land of Youth by James Stephens, Undated (Flat-file-folder 18)
- First Session. Catalogue numbers 1 to 238 by Frederick B. Adams Jr, March 22, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- The Collected Novels of Conrad Aiken by Conrad Aiken, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
- The Tempering of Eugene O' Neill by Doris M. Alezander, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Who Lost an American? By Nelson Algren, Undate (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Western Star by Stephen Vincent Benet, 1943 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- William Black at Home by William Black, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Nova Express by William S. Burroughs, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Windsor Magazine: Drink until the Third and Fourth Generation by Sir Hall Caine, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Love and the Lieutenant by Robert W. Chambers, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Neil Young by Tom Clark, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
- An Address at the Kingston Academy by George William Curtis, June 25, 1891 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- The Catacombs by William Demby, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Meet my Maker the Mad Molecule by J. P. Donleavy, September 23, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- One of the Children is Crying by Coleman Dowell, August 24, 1967; Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
- El Corno Emplumado Issue #30, April 1969 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Forms 3-4 by Theodore Enslin, Undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Forms 1 by Theodore Enslin, Undated (Box 4, Folder 2)
- The Poems, Undated (Box 4, Folder 3)
- The Bristol Fales Family Series II, Subseries S by De Coursey Fales, Undated (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Freedom - When? by James Farmer (Box 4, Folder 5)
- No Foolin' by Edna Ferber, Undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Jews without Money by Michael Gold, Undated (Box 4, Folder 7-8)
- The Senator's Last Night by Francis Hackett (Box 4, Folder 9)
- My Life, Vol. 3 by Frank Harris, Undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Bankers, Bones, and Beetles by Geoffrey Hellman, Undated (Box 5, Folder 2-4)
- Other Publications: Heritage by Geoffrey Hellman, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Other Publications: Saturday Review of Literature, Undated (Box 5, Folder 6)
- The Old Man and the Sea by Ernest Hemingway, Undated (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Looking up at leaves by Barbara Howes, Undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
- The Casket Letters and The Climber's Cook by Violet Hunt, Undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
- The Door by Storm Jameson, Undated (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Robin, The Red Swan by J. Jenkins, Undated (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
- The Complete Poems of D. H. Lawrence by D. H. Lawrence, Undated (Box 6, Folder 3-4)
- Carotid Cornucopius by Christopher Grieve [Hugh MadDiarmid], Undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Everything that rises must converge by Flannery O'Connor, Undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Ibsen's Last Testaments Introduction by John Glassner; Translation by Arvid Paulson, Undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Days of Loneliness by August Strindberg; Translated by Arvid Paulson, Undated (Box 7, Folder 2)
- Errata Sheet, Eight Expressionist Plays by August Strindberg; Translated by Arvid Paulson, Undated (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Seven Plays by Strindberg, Introduction by John Glassner; Translation by Arvid Paulson, Undated (Box 7, Folder 4)
- The Dance of Death by August Strindberg; Translated by Arvid Paulson, Undated (Box 7, Folder 5)
- The natives of Hemso by August Strindberg; Introduction by Richard B. Vowles, Translation by Arvid Paulson, Undated (Box 7, Folder 6)
- World Historical Plays: The Nightingale of Wittenberg (Luther); The Lamb and the Beast (Christ); Through Deserts to Ancestrial Lands (Moses); and Nellas (Socrates); Introduction by Gunnar Ollen; Translation by Arvid Paulson, Undated (Box 7, Folder 7, 9)
- The Scapegoat by August Strindberg; Translated by Arvid Paulson, Undated (Box 7, Folder 8)
- The Strindberg Reader (with notes); translated by Arvid Paulson, Undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Shadows in Paradise by Erich Maria Remarque, Undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Heaven by Erich Maria Remarque, Undated (Box 8, Folder 3-4)
- Signal, Series 2, Folder 1, Undated (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Letters to C. H. C. Pirie-Gordon by Frederick Rolfe (Baron Corvo) (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Baron Corvo by Frederick Rolfe, 1860-1960 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- The Orgy by Muriel Rukeyser, Undated (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Mazel and Schlimazel by Isaae Bashevis Singer, Undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
- The Wallace by Sydney Goodsir Smith, Undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
- Bombs away by John Steinbeck, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Along the Ridge by Edward Streeter, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Dere Mabel by Edward Streeter, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Ham Martin by Edward Streeter, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
- John Milton: Clarion Voices of Freedom by Flora Strousse, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Wilde at Oxford by Alphonse James Albert Symons, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Angel Hair, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Unidentified, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Corrected Proof of Emblems for the Little Dells, and Nooks, and Corners of Paradise by Jonathan Williams, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Mahler by Jonathan Williams, Undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Geraldine Bradshaw by Calder Willingham, Undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Disentangling Old Percy by Pelham Grenville Wodehouse, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Native Son by Richard Wright, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- The Pitch, undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
- The Art of Fiction XXI, Ernest Hemingway, undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
- Unidentified, undated (Box 9, Folder 3)
- Lincoln, The Man of the People, Edwin Markham, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 4)
- Albert Sears, A Novel by Millen Brand, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 5)
- Albert Sears, A Novel by Millen Brand, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- The Night in Lisbon, Erich Maria Remarque, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 7)
- Love and the Lieutenant, Robert W. Chambers, undated (Box 9, Folder 8)
- Water I Slip Into at Night, Words by Margaret Randall, Drawings by Felipe Ehrenberg, undated (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Shadows in Paradise, Erich Maria Remarque, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 10)
- The man who knew Kennedy, VanceBourjaily, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 11)